

Siddharth Aggarwal
Procurement & Contracts
(Mechanical Engineer)
FCC Elecromechanical LLC
Riyadh

**Bachelor of Technology – Mechanical Engineering** 

siddharthaggarwal07@gmail.com

+966-544623920, +91-9953833678

**Personal Details** 

Father's Name: Bharat Bhusan

Date of Birth: 07-Nov-1990
Maritial Status: Married
Nationality: Indian

Language Known: English &

Hindi

Saudi & Indian Valid Driving

License

#### **Permanent Address**

Flat No. 262, Sector 4 Dwarka, New Delhi, India

**Passport Details** 

Passport No. J8646437

Date of Issue: 01/08/2011
Date of Expiry: 31/07/2021

Visa Status: Engineer Visa Employment (Transferrable)

### **OBJECTIVES**

To realize the full extent of my potentials by exploring the different avenues open to utilize my skills. Aim to be a part of a company, which provides me with the platform to work on challenging projects there by testing my inherent strengths of being creative & handling pressure well.

### **SKILL & SPECIFICATIONS**

Experience in an Engineering, Procurement and Construction Operations.

Experience in Contract Analyzing, Drafting & Contracts Management.

Knowledge and direct experience in negotiating contracts and offers with Manufacturers and Suppliers.

Ability to analyze BOQ and drawings to understand key requirements.

Ability to identify cost estimation & cost reduction opportunities.

Proficiency with Primavera & SAP.

Effective verbal and written communication skills.

### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

6.5 Years' experience in Contract's, Procurement and Engineering. Working experience in variety of projects; Metro, tunnel and industrial sector.

**Designation: Procurement & Contract's Engineer (Mechanical)** 

Company: M/s Fomento de Construcciones y Contratas (FCC Spain),

Riyadh, Saudi Arabia

**Profile**: FCC from Spain is a leading contractor in Europe over 100 years' experience in Construction, electromechanical installations in different urban subway lines, metros, infrastructure projects both in Spain and abroad.

**Duration**: Since April 2015 to present

Reporting to: Procurement & Contracts Manager and Project Director

Project: Metro Riyadh Construction & MEP works for Line-4, 5 & 6

(24 Stations, 22 km tunnel with TBM and 44 km Elevated

metro Corridor.)

Value : \$ 8.5 Billion

Client : AR Riyadh Development Authority (Metro Riyadh)

### **RESPONSIBILITIES**

- Preparing Pre-qualifies bidders, Prepares bidders' lists; Forms bid packages, Issues bid requests, Coordinates bidders' questions, Receives bids, Technical Bid Evaluations, Commercial Bid Evaluation, Purchase Orders, Frame work agreement and Sub Contract Agreements and secures approvals in accordance with established procedures; Preparing contracts in accordance with Client Approvals.
- Analyze all suppliers in order to select the most suitable suppliers who are able to deliver high quality products at competitive pricing and can fulfil technical requirements.
- Negotiate with suppliers on lead-time, cost and quality so as to obtain the maximum benefit for the company.
- Responsible for preparing, examining, analyzing, negotiating, and revising contracts that involve the purchase or sale of goods or services such as equipment, materials, supplies, or products.
- Assist Procurement Manager/Project Director in tender processing and technical meeting related with negotiation.
- Define and maintain documented category and supplier strategies using market and competitive data
- Liaise with suppliers on delivery schedule so as to ensure on-time deliveries of final product.
- ♣ Develop, implement and drive the procurement strategies in order to meet cost savings targets.
- Supplier Relationship Management Categorization of suppliers, Rationalization of suppliers, establishing the Competitor base for existing suppliers and dispute resolution with suppliers
- Supporting the implementation of engineering changes to existing parts, ensuring supplier is aware of new requirements, specs, quantities, dates, up revs of parts and reviewing cost/inventory impact.
- Create monthly performance reviews and reports focusing on overall sourcing requirements.
- ♣ Ensure commercial, legal and contractual compliances in all the procurement transactions.
- Adopt appropriate supplier management methodologies and procurement strategies in purchasing to secure better prices.
- Train team on effective procurement processes and strategy.
- Coordinate with vendor on continuous quality improvement.

**Designation: Mechanical Engineer** 

Company: M/s. Hindustan Construction Company Ltd. India

Profile : Plant Machinery Procurement & MEP Contracts Management.

**Duration**: Since January 2013 to April 2015

**Reporting to: Project Manager** 

Project : Delhi Metro - Under Ground Stations and Twin Tunnel

Value : INR 6.41 billion

Client : Delhi Metro Rail Corporation (DMRC)

**Designation: Graduate Engineer Trainee (Mechanical)** 

Company: M/s. Uvimac Solutions Pvt Ld

**Duration**: Since May 2012 to January 2013

**Reporting to: Plant Manager** 

Project : Manufacturing & Assembling of Car Units for Mahindra & Mahindra.

## **ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION**

- Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech) specialized in Mechanical Engineering from Krishna Engineering
   College Ghaziabad recognized by Uttar Pradesh Technical University 2008-2012.
- ♣ Higher Secondary School (XII) from CBSE Board 2006-2008
- Secondary School (X) from CBSE Board 2005 2006
- Certified Mechanical Engineer from Saudi Council of Engineers.

## **COMPUTER KNOWLEDGE**

ASNT NDT Level II : Liquid Penetrant Testing [Certification No. – 14070309]

Magnetic Particle Testing [Certification No. - 14070402]

Diploma : MCAD (AutoCAD and Pro/E)

Software Packages : SAP, Aconex, Primavera, Pro-QMS, Adobe Photoshop, Autodesk, MS Office

Basic programming : C

### STUDY PROJECTS

- ♣ HOVERCRAFT PROTOTYPE DEVELOPMENT A hovercraft, also known as an air-cushion vehicle or ACV, is a craft capable of travelling over land, water, mud or ice and other surfaces both at speed and when stationary.
- Image Processing ROBOT & Digital security system.
- Conducts Seminar on Powder metallurgy, Manufacturing, Robotics and presentations.

# **DECLARATION**

I hereby declared that the information furnished above is true to the best of my knowledge.

Place: Riyadh

SIDDHARTH AGGARWAL